# **MUHAMAD ARIFFUDIN**

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Johor Baharu, Johor | +60 11 1067 3172 | muhamad-ariffudin.github.io muhamadariffudin49@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/muhamad-ariffudin/

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

Passionate UIUX Developer with a degree in Software Engineering. With 4 years of experience in the industry. I am a quick learner who is curious and enjoys solving problems with the best solution. I work well in teams and am eager to apply my knowledge and experience to your company and enhance my professional career.

## PROFESSIONAL SKILL

- UI & UX Design, Product Design
- HTML5, CSS, JavaScript
- PHP, JAVA, ASP.NET
- Laravel, React JS, React Native
- Kotlin, Swift, Flutter
- SQL, My SQL, Firebase
- Wordpress, Webflow, Shopify

#### TECHNICAL SKILL

- Visual Studio Code, Visual studio, Eclipse
- Net Bean, Android Studio, X Code
- Git Hub, Git Lab, Behance, Dribble
- Photoshop, Illustrate, Premiere pro
- Adobe XD, Flgma, Sketch, Miro, InVision
- Wireframe, Prototyping, Research, Usability testing
- SEO, Google analytic, Google & Facebook Ads

#### EDUCATION

## **BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering**

Asia Pacific University of Technology & Innovation

CGPA: 2.65/4

## Dip in Information Technology (Programming)

Polytechnic Balik Pulau

CGPA: 2.86/4

2018 - 2020

2015 - 2017

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software UI/UX Developer [Full Time]

Alphacore Technology Sdn. Bhd. [Kuala Lumpur]

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

- Develop a healthcare system and an HRM system using the Laravel PHP framework, ReactJS for the front-end framework and participate in the whole software development life cycle, from planning to implementation.
- Worked with business analysts, product managers, designers, and developers to ensure that the designs were properly executed. I used prototype tools like Adobe XD, Figma, Miro, and Sketch to express ideas, and I also illustrated design concepts using drawings and wireframes.
- Contributed to the creation of the frontend, backend, and API for the healthcare, HRMS system. Debugging, issue resolution, database maintenance, and system deployment.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineer [Full Time]

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021

- SRG Asia Pacific Sdn. Bhd. [Kuala Lumpur]
- Collaborate in a software development team that created a contact centre dialer report application with RESTful API connection and a MySQL database while utilising Agile Methodology, JAVA, and PHP (Laravel).
- Supported and maintained the call center dialer software (vici\_dial) during critical periods for any troubleshooting, created and implemented automated unit testing in PHP and report generated to ensure business logic satisfies user requirements and detect code issues.
- Created well-designed, tested code on a consistent basis utilising best practises for website development, including mobile and responsive site design. Create webpages and user interfaces that include data from backend services and database.

## Web Developer [Contract]

May 2020 - Aug 2020

## Samurai Paint Sdn. Bhd. [Johor Bahru]

- Created websites and user interfaces, using standard HTML/CSS/Javascript, while incorporating data from back-end and database.
- Perform UI designs and coding, creating reusable objects and templates, wireframes for web pages and email templates, manage maintenance, updates, expansions, and scaling of each design.
- Develop or validate testing schedules, addressing all browsers and devices to ensure various computers can access content using Docker.

## Web UI/UX Developer [Full Time]

Jun 2019 - May 2020

## George Healthcare Sdn. Bhd. [Kuala Lumpur]

- Developed a healthcare system Healtopedia using PHP and a MySQL database, the app was built with React, and the UI/UX was designed with Sketch and Figma, and participated in the whole software development life cycle using SCRUM Methodology.
- Prototype storytelling to allow audiences to experience ideas and concepts such as interactive digital storyboards, iterative web development, and mobile applications.
- Completed minor changes requested by customers quickly and thoroughly, plan larger projects, interact with colleagues, and contribute unique ideas to improve present websites with responsive web.

## Web UI/UX Developer [Full Time]

May 2017 - Apr 2018

## Web Creative Solutions Sdn. Bhd. [Johor Bahru]

- Contribute in the HRMSystem and the e-commerce project, resolve issues, do quality assurance testing on the system, and work on the front and back ends of the system (using PHP), as well as the UI/UX.
- Collaborate with internal teams to develop, design, and implement solutions. Aided in the implementation of payment applications, which are currently utilised by all of the company's e-commerce clients.
- Worked closely with the client during the design and implementation phases to ensure that the final product satisfies the requirements.

## Web UI/UX Developer [Internship]

Feb 2017 - Apr 2017

#### DreamSpace Sdn. Bhd. [Johor Bahru]

- Improve client business processes and increase efficiency by soliciting input and delivering project status updates.
- Develop and enhance existing system module. Attend SCRUM sessions and learn about the software development life cycle.